<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-09T18:18:03+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Martin Klein</title><subtitle>Energy etc.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Wenn wir uns verstehen (1/10)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/25/short_story1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wenn wir uns verstehen (1/10)" /><published>2019-02-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-02-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/25/short_story1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/25/short_story1.html">&lt;p&gt;Sie stand dort, als sei nichts gewesen, dabei war ihr gerade etwas klar geworden, an das sie für immer glauben würde: Die Menschen sollten meditieren, und zwar täglich. Du kannst nicht erwarten, dass dir irgendjemand irgendwann eine Lebensaufgabe stellt, dachte sie, nein, das musst du schon selbst tun. Und wie? Du hältst inne, gibst dir ein wenig Perspektive, meditierst und schaltest endlich dein Reptiliengehirn aus. Nur so merken wir, in welchem Abenteuerroman wir eigentlich gelandet sind. Sie war auch deswegen hier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was dachte ihr Reptiliengehirn? In der Auslage lagen die Transistoren wie Käfer zur Schau. Sandra war sich sicher, am richtigen Ort zu suchen. In dieser Halle mussten die Einzelteile für den ersten Prototypen gekauft worden sein, so hatte es dort gestanden - als der Reddit-Artikel in ihren Feed gerutscht war, hatte sie leise „Stop“ sagen müssen um ihren Freund zum Schweigen zu bringen. Diese Erfindung würde, sie war sich sicher, die Welt für immer verändern, und sie wollte dabei sein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Das macht doch keinen Sinn, hatten sie alle zu ihr gesagt, du weißt doch gar nicht, wie man Smartphone-Kameras repariert, nicht mal das, du hast noch nie ein elektronisches Gerät auseinander gebaut, du studierst Kommunikationswissenschaften!, und selbst wenn es funktionert, dein Argument zählt nicht, du fliegst tausende Kilometer, um eine gebrochene Linse auszutauschen, von den Emissionen, die du beim Flug ausstößt, kannst du dir doch 10 neue Handys kaufen, mindestens, und außerdem isst du dein Eis mit Plastiklöffeln, also sag nicht, dass du das für die Umwelt und gegen unsere Ressourcenverschwendung tust!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perspektive also? Sie sah auf in Richtung Leuchtreklame, auf der groß geschrieben stand: 廉价电池待售, was sie natürlich nicht verstand, und fand sich inmitten des Elektronikladens an der Shoppingmeile Huaqiang. Dies, so sagte man ihr, sei der größte Elektronik-Bauteil-Einzelhandel der Welt, und sie glaubte ihnen, denn man sah Marktstände und Theken bis ans Ende des Horizonts - wenn es so etwas wie einen Horizont innerhalb eines Gebäudes gab - auf jeden Fall war es das erste Mal, dass sie darüber nachdachte, ob es auch einen Horizont in Gebäuden geben könnte.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shenzhen sei die am schnellsten gewachsene Stadt der Welt. Vor ein paar Jahrzehnten noch ein Dorf an der Grenze zu Hong Kong, lebten hier heute angeblich so viele Menschen wie in London, Paris und Berlin zusammen. Sie hatte einmal gehört, dass die glaubwürdigsten Lügen diejenigen Aussagen seien, die fast der Wahrheit entsprächen, und sie war tatsächlich wegen Elektronik-Bauteilen nach China gereist. Aber vor allem wollte sie Chloé und Annelies treffen, von denen in diesem Reddit-Artikel die Rede war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dies ist der Anfang einer ca. 10-teiligen Kurzgeschichte. Fortsetzung folgt. Schau nächsten Monat wieder vorbei :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sie stand dort, als sei nichts gewesen, dabei war ihr gerade etwas klar geworden, an das sie für immer glauben würde: Die Menschen sollten meditieren, und zwar täglich. Du kannst nicht erwarten, dass dir irgendjemand irgendwann eine Lebensaufgabe stellt, dachte sie, nein, das musst du schon selbst tun. Und wie? Du hältst inne, gibst dir ein wenig Perspektive, meditierst und schaltest endlich dein Reptiliengehirn aus. Nur so merken wir, in welchem Abenteuerroman wir eigentlich gelandet sind. Sie war auch deswegen hier.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My favorite music of 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/01/best_of_2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My favorite music of 2018" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/01/best_of_2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/01/best_of_2018.html">&lt;p&gt;A fun part of the end-of-year festivities was always to read the “best of” lists and learn what greatness one had missed. Resident Advisor and other electronic music outlets stopped to release storted lists because, as they say, they cannot bring the tracks in a definite order. But that is exactly what I expect from music critiques - guidance and opinion in times of abundance. So I created my own completely subjective top 10 of 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-against-all-logic---now-u-got-me-hooked&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;10. Against All Logic - Now U Got Me Hooked&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QP5KowYeR-w&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That podcast was something else — enigmatically called Against All Logic #279, it never failed to propell me forward and calm me down into a flow state.
“Against All Logic“, it turned out, is the club alias of Nicolas Jaar under which he recently released an album called “2012-2017”. The songs are mix-downs of live versions Jaar played over time. “Now U Got Me Hooked” is luckily part of that album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-kettenkarussell---maybe&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;9. Kettenkarussell - Maybe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had to be an Youtube underground hit. First, the algorithms pushed it into my playlists, later I voluntarily returned on my own. At the time of writing, the track has already more than 3 million plays, quite a number for a channel for „lofi house“ aficionados. But the channel belongs to “Slav“, who also featured “DJ Boring - Winona“, and the record itself is signed by the notorious “Giegling“ label. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/hpKlCKL9FsM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-dj-koze---pick-up&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;8. DJ Koze - Pick Up&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a simple man. When I hear a groove that never resolves and tickles that sweet sweet French house nerve like “Music Sounds Better With You“ or “One More Time“, I hit buy, no question. Even more so when this is so crackingly produced by one of the Master’s himself - DJ Koze. The video is a hilarious gem too.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JE63vMzb3UE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-dj-existential-crisis---raised-by-wolves&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;7. DJ Existential Crisis - Raised By Wolves&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A basement full of smoke and flashing lights. The soundsystem banging. People cheering. DJ Existential Crisis is another alias of master producer Paul Woolford / Special Request. No wonder. I got hooked by that baseline at first listen. After all we’ve been through﻿. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UHRPF1g2Vfg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-djrum---blue-violet&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;6. DJRum - Blue Violet&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Djrum’s tracks are complex, fast, physical, yet often full of strangely attracting tenderness. Blue Violet is no exception. I adore the level of detail in all his productions.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/McFnqbpevjw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-breach---turtle-dance&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;5. Breach - Turtle Dance&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A perfect combination of playfulness and “out there.“ My favorite moment is around the 4 minute mark - would fit perfectly to an outdoor festival, late-night, Croatian coast.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/B39kqzrXp1E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-bicep---opal-four-tet-remix&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. Bicep - Opal (Four Tet Remix)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love the album, love the remix. The combination of groove and feels has made this a go to track for me during the whole year. The strings in the beginning started to be comfort zone. Really hard to get this in electronic music.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XTw-NrqKigs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-skee-mask---flyby-vfr&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Skee Mask - Flyby Vfr&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drums like Floating Points. Insane breaks. And the feels. Nothing to add here.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WrxXObHUyVg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-overmono---daisy-chain&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Overmono - Daisy Chain&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Bass music” is seldomly gentle, but this track, albeit quite rough and low, has such a sweet melancholy to it. Favorite moment: Past minute 5, when the clicks collaps and the heaviness of the beat sets in again. Tessela’s characteristic vocal chops are the icing on the cake.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dTFO5_ERBq0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-aleksandir---yamaha&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Aleksandir - Yamaha&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here too, the Youtube algorithm had flooded the track into my feeds. And boy was I happy. I didn’t know Aleksandir, nor the label Tessellate before, but this track has every right to &amp;gt;3 million clicks by now. The synth progression and the crispness of the production made this my favorite of 2018. A track whose rightful success is the perfect embodiment of the potential of our times.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OnW6rQ_z9Ug&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A fun part of the end-of-year festivities was always to read the “best of” lists and learn what greatness one had missed. Resident Advisor and other electronic music outlets stopped to release storted lists because, as they say, they cannot bring the tracks in a definite order. But that is exactly what I expect from music critiques - guidance and opinion in times of abundance. So I created my own completely subjective top 10 of 2018.</summary></entry></feed>